Guide to the New-York Historical Society Theatrical Portrait Collection circa 1800-1985 (bulk, 1850-1920) PR 104
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Individuals, undated
  - Subseries I.A. Individuals (small format), undated
    - Individuals (small) "R" (continued), undated (Offsite-box 32)
      Raymond, John T.
      Reddisch, Meta
      Rehan, Ada (3 folders)
      Reszke
      Reynolds, Genevieve
      Rhea, Hortense
      Rice, Fanny
      Rigl, Emily
      Rignold, George
      Ristori, Adelaide
    - Individuals (small) "R" (continued), undated (Offsite-box 33)
      Robe, Annie
      Robson, Stuart
      Rogers
      Rolson, Stuart
      Roze, Marie
      Russell
      Russell, Annie
      Russell, Lillian (4 folders)
      Russell, Sol Smith
      Russell, Tommy
    - Individuals (small) "S", undated (Offsite-box 34)
      Sa - Sr miscellaneous
    - Individuals (small) "S" (continued), undated (Offsite-box 35)
      Ss - Sz miscellaneous
      Salvini, Alexander
      Salvini, Tommaso
      Sandow, Eugen
      Scalchi, Sofia
      Sembrich, Marcella
      Sheridan, W. E. (William Edward)
      Siddons, Scott, Mrs.
    - Individuals (small) "S" (continued), undated (Offsite-box 36)
      Smith
      Sothern, Edward Askew
      Sothern, E. H. (Edward Hugh)
      Stanhope, Adeline
      Stanley
      Starr, Frances
      Steele, Joseph F.
      Stevenson, Charles A.
      Stoddart, James Henry
      Strakosch
      Strakosch, Moritz
    - Individuals (small) "T", undated (Offsite-box 37)
      T miscellaneous
      Taber, Robert
      Taylor
      Tearle, Osmond
      Tempest, Marie
      Templeton, Fay (includes cabinet card, gift of the La Porte County Historical Society Museum, accession no. PPAC.2022.020)
      Terry, Ellen (includes cabinet card, gift of the La Porte County Historical Society Museum, accession no. PPAC.2022.020)
      Thomas
      Thompson, Lydia
      Thorne, Charles R. Jr.
      Tree, Herbert Beerbohm, Sir
    - Individuals (small) "U", undated (Offsite-box 38)
      U miscellaneous
      Urquhart, Isabelle
    - Individuals (small) "V", undated (Offsite-box 38)
      V miscellaneous
      Varian, Nina
      Vokes, Rosina
    - Individuals (small) "W", undated (Offsite-box 38)
      W - Wel miscellaneous
    - Individuals (small) "W" (continued), undated (Offsite-box 39)
      Wen - Wz miscellaneous
      Wainwright, Marie
      Wallack
      Wallack, Lester
      Waller
      Ward
      Warfield, David
      Weathersby, Eliza
      Webb
      Webster, Lizzie
      Wendell, Evert Jansen
    - Individuals (small) "W" (continued), undated (Offsite-box 40)
      Wheatley, William
      Williams
      Williams, Barney
      Williams, Hattie
      Wilson, Francis
      Wittkowska, Marta
      Wood
      Wood, John, Mrs.
      Wyndham, Charles
    - Individuals (small) "Y", undated (Offsite-box 40)
      Y miscellaneous
      Yeamans
      Yoel, Peggy King
    - Individuals (small) "Z", undated (Offsite-box 40)
      Z miscellaneous
      Zula Zeleah ("Circassian Beauty"; cabinet card, gift of the La Porte County Historical Society Museum, accession no. PPAC.2022.020)
    - Individuals (small) "composite portraits", undated (Offsite-box 40)
  - Subseries I.B. Individuals (medium format), undated
    - Individuals (medium) "A", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Alda, Frances (2 images)
      Anderson, Mary
      Anglin, Margaret (3 images)
      Apollo Musical Club
      Aston, Tony
      Augusta, La Petite
    - Individuals (medium) "B", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Banci, Alessandro
      Bancroft, Squire
      Barry, Billy
      Baxter, Pete
      Behr, Carrie
      Booth (separate folder)
      ....Booth, Agnes
      ....Booth, Edwin (3 images)
      ....Booth, John Wilkes (4 images)
      ....Booth, Junius Brutus (2 images)
      ....Booth, Rachel
      Bowers. Mrs. D. P.
      Brignoli, Pasquale
      Brougham, John
      Bryant, Dan
      Bull, Ole (2 images)
      Burton, William E. (William Evans)
    - Individuals (medium) "C", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Campanini, Cleofonte
      Carey, Eleanor
      Caron, Rose
      Carter, Helen E. H.
      Cary, Annie Louise
      Celeste, Madame (Celine)
      Child, Edmund Bramhill (2 images)
      Christy, Edwin Pearce
      Coghlan, Rose (3 images)
      Collier, William
      Cook, Augustus
      Cooke, George Frederick
      Coquelin, Constant (2 images)
      Cornell, Katharine
      Crane, William H.
      Crosman, Henrietta
      Cushman, Pauline
    - Individuals (medium) "D", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Dailey, Peter F.
      Damrosch, Leopold
      Davenport, Fanny
      De Bar, Ben
      Dempsey, John
      Dewey
      Dougherty, Hughey
      Downing, Robert
      Drew, John (2 images)
      Duse, Eleonora
      Dyck, Ernest van
    - Individuals (medium) "E", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Eddinger, Wallace
      Elssler, Fanny
    - Individuals (medium) "F", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Fechter, Charles
      Fish, Nicholas (2 images)
      Fisher, Charles (2 images)
      Fiske, Minnie Maddern
      Florence, Mrs. W. J. (William Jermyn)
      Forrest, Edwin (2 images)
      French, Colonel
    - Individuals (medium) "G", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Galli-Curci, Amelita
      Garden, Mary (2 images)
      Gaylor, Bobby
      Geddes, Norman Bel
      Gilligan, Helen
      Goodwin, Myra
      Gordon, Amy
      Griffin, Richard
      Gulick, Earl
    - Individuals (medium) "H", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Hall, M. Andre
      Hamlin, Tom
      Harris, Estelle
      Harris, William (2 images)
      Hart, Tony, including Gallant 69th (2 images)
      Haynes, Minnie Gale
      Hepburn, Katharine
      Holland, Mrs. E. M.
      Hopper, De Wolf (2 images)
      Howard, Cordelia (2 images)
      Hutchinson family (2 images)
    - Individuals (medium) "I", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Irving, Henry, Sir (2 images)
    - Individuals (medium) "J", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Jamieson, William
      Jefferson, Joseph (4 images)
      Johnson, Louise
      Jones, George, Mrs.
      Jones, M. Sissieretta (2 images)
      Juch, Emma
    - Individuals (medium) "K", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Kalich, Bertha
      Kean, Charles John
      Kean, Edmund (3 images)
      Kean, Ellen (2 images)
      Keene, Tom
      Kemble, John Philip
      Kernell, Harry
      Kerrigan and McCarthy
    - Individuals (medium) "L", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Lackaye, Wilton
      Lauder, Sir Harry (2 images)
      Langtry, Lillie (2 images)
      Lecomte
      Lind, Jenny (separate folder; 74 images)
      Little Mac
    - Individuals (medium) "M", undated (Drawer Medium)
      MacGregor, Helen
      Magnier, Marie
      Marlowe, Julia (2 images)
      Mayo, Frank
      Montez, Lola
      Moore, Flora
      Morris, Nina
      Muratore, Lucien
    - Individuals (medium) "N", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Neilson, Adelaide
      Nelson, Miss
      Nethersole, Olga
      Newcomb, Bobby
      Nilsson, Christine (2 images)
      Noria, Jane
    - Individuals (medium) "O", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Otis, Elita Proctor
    - Individuals (medium) "P", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Parker, Louisa V.
      Parodi, Teresi
      Passmore, Walter
      Paul, Mr. and Mrs. Howard
      Paullin, Louise
      Phelps, Samuel
      Piccolomini, Marietta (2 images)
      Pickford, Mary
      Powers, James T.
      Primrose, George
      Proctor, J.
    - Individuals (medium) "R", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Rachel
      Ratchkoff, Bess (Nadia) de
      Rehan, Ada
      Reszke, Jean de
      Rice, Tom
      Robson, Stuart (2 images)
      Rogers, Gus
      Rogers, Max
      Rogers, Will
      Ross, Charles J.
      Rothberg, Elizabeth
      Russell, Annie (2 images)
      Russell, Lillian (10 images)
      Russell, Marie Booth
    - Individuals (medium) "S", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Salvini, Tommaso (3 images)
      Sedgwick, Amy
      Sembrich, Marcella (2 images)
      Scanlan, W. T.
      Schaffer, Josephine (4 images)
      Scheff, Fritzi
      Siddons, Sarah (2 images)
      Skipworth, Alison
      Slezak (2 images)
      Sontag, Henriette
      Sothern, E. H. (Edward Hugh) (separate folder; 15 images)
      Spalding, Albert
      Strauss, Henrietta Treffz
    - Individuals (medium) "T", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Taglioni, Marie
      Tauscher, Johanna
      Terris, William
      Terry, Ellen, Dame (2 images)
      Thompson, Denman
      Thumb, Tom
      Toole, John Lawrence
    - Individuals (medium) "V", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Valentino, Rudolph
      Valleria, Alvian Lohmann (Schoning)
    - Individuals (medium) "W", undated (Drawer Medium)
      Wallack, James William
      Wallack, William
      Walsh, Blanche (2 images)
      Walsh, Mike
      Warren William
      Watkins, Harry
      Weekes, Frederick Delano
      West, Lillie
      Western, Lucille
      Westerner, Lillian
      Williams, Gus
      Winans, Mrs. John
      Wittkowska, Marta (5 images)
  - Subseries I.C. Individuals (large format), undated
    - Individuals (large) "C", undated (Drawer Large)
      Crane, William H. (2 images)
    - Individuals (large) "G", undated (Drawer Large)
      Green, William B.
    - Individuals (large) "L", undated (Drawer Large)
      Lind, Jenny (separate folder; 4 images)
    - Individuals (large) "M", undated (Drawer Large)
      Marlowe, Julia
    - Individuals (large) "P", undated (Drawer Large)
      Patti, Adelina
      Potter, Mrs. James Brown
      Powers, Leland T. (2 images)
    - Individuals (large) "R", undated (Drawer Large)
      Russell, Lillian (separate folder; 5 images)
    - Individuals (large) "S", undated
      Siddons, Sarah
      Siddons, Mrs. Scott
- Series II. Groups, circa 1852-1942, undated
  Portraits are filed alphabetically by name of the group.
  - Subseries II.A. Groups (medium format), 1875-1942, undated
    - Music (medium), 1889-1942, undated (Drawer Medium)
      Henry E. Abbey and Maurice Grau opera artists, 1889
      Hearons Sisters Concert Co., undated
      Mendelsohn Glee Club, 1942
      Montauk Ladies' Quartet, undated
      New York Edison & Consolidated Gas Choral Society, 1926
      Oratorio Society of New York, undated
    - Theatre (medium), 1875-1936, undated (Drawer Medium)
      American Gilbert and Sullivan Association dinner (2 images), 1936
      Bronx Opera Club, (separate folder; 7 images)
      "The Gondoliers," 1931
      "HMS Pinafore," 1929
      "The Mascot," 1933
      "The Mikado," 1928
      "Olivette," 1932
      "Patience," 1929
      "The Sorcerer," 1932
      Callender Minstrel Festival, 1883
      Augustin Daly's company, including John Drew, Ada Rehan, 1884
      Empire Theatre Stock Company, 1903
      Daniel Frohman's Company, 1900
      Harrigan and Hart's Theatre Comique Company, 1875
      John E. Kellerd repertory productions cast (separate folder; 12 images), 1906–1911
      "Hamlet"
      "Macbeth"
      "Merchant of Venice"
      Weber and Fields Company, including Lillian Russell (3 images), undated
  - Subseries II.B. Groups (large format), circa 1852, 1917, 1930
    - Music (large), circa 1852, 1930 (Drawer Large)
      American Bandmasters Association, 1930
      Germania Musical Society, circa 1852
    - Theatre (large), 1917 (Drawer Large)
      "Lest We Forget" poster with portraits of deceased actors, 1917
- Series III. Unidentified, undated
  The unidentified portraits are arranged in two subseries: Small and Medium Format.
  - Subseries III.A. Unidentified (small format), undated
    - Unidentified children (small), undated (Offsite-box 41)
    - Unidentified groups (small), undated (Offsite-box 41)
      Music
      Theatrical
    - Unidentified men (small), undated (Offsite-box 41)
    - Unidentified women (small), undated (Offsite-box 42)
    - Unidentified women (small), undated (Offsite-box 43)
  - Subseries III.B. Unidentified (medium format), undated
    - Unidentified women (medium) (7 images), undated (Drawer Medium)
- Series IV. Productions, 1855-1957, undated
  Images are arranged in three subseries: Small, Medium, and Large Format, then filed thereunder alphabetically by name of production.
  - Subseries IV.A. Productions (small format), 1875-1957, undated
    - Theatre (small), 1875-1917, undated (Offsite-box 44)
      "Geisha," 1907
      "Genevieve de Brabant," undated
      "The Highest Bidder," undated
      "King John," undated
      "Living Art Studies," 1901
      "Miss Multon," 1876
      "Our Boarding House," 1877
      "Pique," 1875–76
      "The Private Secretary," 1885
      "Romeo and Juliet," undated
      "Sweet Lavender," 1888
      "Trilby," 1895
      "Uncle Tom's Cabin," undated
      "Wanderer," 1917
    - Gilbert and Sullivan (small), 1893, 1939, undated (Offsite-box 45)
      "The Mikado," theatrical production 1893
      "The Mikado," movie stills 1939
      "Patience," 1893
      Miscellaneous productions (2 folders), undated
    - Motion Pictures (small), circa 1912-1957, undated (Offsite-box 46)
      "Destiny, or The Soul of a Woman," 1916
      "Eve of the Revolution," 1924
      "Gateway to the West," 1924
      "The Golden Trail," 1920
      "Johnny Tremain," 1957
      "Knickerbocker Holiday," 1944
      "Vanity Fair," 1915
      "Your Wife and Mine," 1919
      Westerns, miscellaneous 1923–31, undated
      Miscellaneous and unidentified circa 1912, undated
  - Subseries IV.B. Productions (medium format), 1880-1939, undated
    - Theatre (medium), 1880-1906, undated (Drawer Medium)
      "Diplomacy," 1901
      "Erminie," undated
      "Hazel Kirke," 1880
      "King Henry IV," undated
      "Merchant of Venice," undated
      "The Princess and the Butterfly" (2 images), 1897
      "Rogers Brothers in Central Park" (2 folders; 11 images), 1900
      "Roi de Lahore," opera production undated
      "Romance" (2 images), undated
      "Sally," undated
      "Septimus" (2 images), undated
      "Sunny South," undated
      "The Tourists," 1906
      "Yankee Circus on Mars," undated
      Unidentified (6 images), undated
    - Gilbert and Sullivan (medium), 1939, undated (Drawer Medium)
      "The Gondoliers" (4 images), undated
      "HMS Pinafore" (4 images), undated
      "Iolanthe" (3 images), undated
      "The Mikado" theatrical production (7 images), undated
      "The Mikado" motion picture stills (6 images), 1939
      "Patience" (4 images), undated
      "Thespis," undated
      Unidentified (2 images), undated
  - Subseries IV.C. Productions (large format), 1855, 1887
    - Theatre (large), 1855, 1887 (Drawer Large)
      "Romeo and Juliet" (Margaret Mather production), 1855
      "Taming of the Shrew," 1887
- Series V. Capezio Dance Portraits, circa 1943
  Portraits are filed alphabetically by sitter.
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "A", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Alonso, Alicia
    Argentinita
    Asquith, Ruby
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "B", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Bales, William
    Baronova, Irina
    Bettis, Valerie
    Bolender, Todd
    Bowman, Patricia
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "C", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Cansinos
    Caton, Edward
    Chase, Lucia
    Chouteau, Yvonne
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "D", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Danilova, Alexandra
    De Mille, Agnes
    Delza, Sophia
    Dolinoff, Alexis
    Dollar, William
    Dudley, Jane
    Dunham, Katharine
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "E", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Eglevsky, Andre
    Essen, Viola
    Etheridge, Dorothy
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "F", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Fay, Vivien
    Flier, Freda
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "G", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Gansert, Jack
    Graham, Martha
    Grantzeva, Tatiana
    Guerard, Roland
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "H", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Haakon, Paul
    Hawkins, Erick
    Hightower, Rosella
    Holm, Hanya
    Humphrey, Doris
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "I", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Istomina, Anna
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "J", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Jeanne, Marie
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "K", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Kay, Lisan
    Kaye, Nora
    Kelly, Gene
    Koner, Pauline
    Krassovska, Nathalie
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "L", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Laing, Hugh
    Lazowsky, Yurek
    Lee, Kathryn
    Lichine, David
    Littlefield, Dorothie
    Loring, Eugene
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "M", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Markova, Alice
    Maslow, Sophie
    Massine, Leonide
    Mayfair, Mitzi
    McCracken, Joan
    Miller, Ann
    Montes, Monna
    Moore, Lillian
    Moylan, Mary Ellen
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "N", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Nancy and Michael
    Nemchinova, Vera
    Nimura, Yeichi
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "O", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Osato, Sono
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "P", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Page, Ruth
    Petroff, Paul
    Platt, Marc
    Powell, Eleanor
    Primus, Pearl
    Pryor, Ruth
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "R", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Reed, Janet
    Riabouchinska, Tatiana
    Robbins, Jerome
    Robinson, Bill
    Rosario and Antonio
    Roudenko, Lobov
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "S", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Sergava, Katharine
    Shawn, Ted
    Slavenska, Mia
    Stroganova, Nina
    Stuart and Lea
    Svetlova, Marina
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "T", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Tallchief, Maria
    Tapps, George
    Tennis, Eleanor
    Toumanova, Tamara
    Toy, Dorothea
    Tudor, Antony
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "V", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Valentinoff, Valya
    Varkas, Leon
  - Capezio Dance Portraits "Z", circa 1943 (Offsite-box 47)
    Zorina, Vera